adaptec.com 2009-06-19

# Adaptec - Privacy Policy

Last updated on September 1, 2007 (V4.4)

Adaptec, Inc. (“Adaptec”) wants you, our customers and visitors to [www.adaptec.com](http://www.adaptec.com/) and all of our other Web sites, to know how information about you is used. Our privacy policy is set out below and describes our information gathering and usage practices. Please read Adaptec's Terms of Use for our Web site(s). By visiting our Web site(s) you agree to accept the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy.

Adaptec wants to take this opportunity to assure you that we do not rent, sell or make otherwise available user information provided via our Web site(s) to third parties except as specified in this Privacy Policy.

We are firmly committed to guarding the confidence you have placed in our company and to use any information you volunteer responsibly and professionally. We strive to collect only that information that we think is necessary for our legitimate business interests such as improving marketing of our products, meeting the needs of and educating customers, resolving customer disputes and ensuring that our proprietary information is protected. If you do not want to share personal data, please read below for information on how to opt out or change personal information Adaptec collects from you.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this privacy statement, please contact us via e-mail or phone Adaptec Customer Service at the following numbers:   
**  
For North America:**  
Adaptec Privacy Policy  Or phone Adaptec Customer Service at either 1-800-959-7274 or 1-408-957-2550

 **Hours of business are:**  
Monday - Friday (except holidays) 9:00 AM - 6:00 PM U.S. Central Time

**For EMEA:**   

or phone   
+49.89.43.66.55.45 (English)  
+49.89.43.66.55.25 (German)  
+49.89.43.66.55.35 (French)

 **Hours of business are:  
** 09:00 - 12:00, 13:00 - 16:00 CET

Our Web site visitors from Europe should note that, as a US company, Adaptec collects data from you within the EEA and reserves the right to transfer the same outside the EEA for processing and storage. Adaptec is certified on the Safe Harbor List and abides by the principles set forth in the Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

This policy also applies to personal information collected by Adaptec (Hong Kong) Limited (" **Adaptec Australia** ") including personal information collected through the www.adaptec.com.au Web site. For questions on the privacy statement, you may contact Adaptec’s Customer Service in Australia at the email addresses or telephone numbers listed below and during the local hours of business of 9.00am to 5.00pm Australia EST: 

**Adaptec Australia :  
** Unit E1, 15 Forrester St  
Kingsgrove NSW 2208  
Australia  
t: 612-9503-1555   
f: 612-9503-1500  

This policy discloses our information gathering and usage practices for the following Web sites:

---|---  
  
Contents:   

Product Registration   
"A.S.K. Us" or Online Support Request   
Sweepstakes, Contests & Promotions   
Online Store & Electronic Software  
 Adaptec Connect, Adaptec Platinum and Adaptec Europe Partner Program  
 Online Surveys  
 Sharing Information with Other Companies  
 Message Boards  
 Notifications of Changes  
 Unsubscribing/Opt-Out  
 Correcting or Updating your Personal Info  
 Information We Automatically Collect  
 Privacy and Children  
 Security  
 Contact Us

Product Registration and Online Support Request "A.S.K. Us"   

In order to improve our problem resolution process through better product and case tracking, Adaptec's tech support department has implemented online product registration and technical support services. We require contact information and either a product serial number, server number or TSID (Technical Support Identification) number to identify your product. This information is used to manage your case, notify you when necessary of issues related to your product and together with your voluntary responses to our marketing survey, is used to analyze our customer base in aggregate. Occasionally, we may send emails to give customers information we think you will find useful, such as information about new features, products or promotions. When we email you, we will always provide instructions explaining how to unsubscribe so you will not receive our emails in the future. You may also opt-out of receiving future Adaptec and/or partner communications by submitting your request through our online feedback form or by submitting your request in writing as described in the section entitled: **Unsubscribing/Opt-Out.**

Adaptec does collect off-line customer data (such as your name and address) through product registration cards that are included in some Adaptec products. Adaptec will treat your information as if it was collected through this Web site.

Sweepstakes, Contests & Promotions   

Adaptec occasionally sponsors sweepstakes, contests and promotions. We use contact data from our promotions to send users information we think you will find useful, such as information about new products or promotions. When we email you, we will always provide instructions explaining how to unsubscribe from these specific mailings, so you will not receive these mailings in the future.

Online Store - North America only

To process your order we require your name, billing address, phone number, email address, shipping address and credit card information. We use this information to process your order and, if any questions arise, to contact you about your order. In general, we will try to contact you first by email and only if that fails, or if time is critical, will we try to contact you by phone. Your order is processed, on our behalf, by Commerce5 for the North America store [],providers of e-commerce services (or such other provider as Adaptec may select from time to time with notice on an updated Privacy Policy statement). View Commerce5's Privacy and Security Statement. We may send special news or offers that we think may be valuable to you. If you would prefer not to receive these in the future, please email [adaptecstore@adaptec.com.](mailto:adaptecstore@adaptec.com.) Put UNSUBSCRIBE ADAPTEC at the top of the message body. Alternatively, you may unsubscribe by sending your request in writing as described in the section entitled: **Unsubscribing/Opt-Out.** In the event you are a reseller entering through [www.adaptecconnect.com](http://www.adaptecconnect.com/) please refer to the section below regarding information collected

Adaptec Partner, Channel or Alliance Progams   

From time to time, Adaptec sponsors partner, channel or alliance programs accessible through Web sites via [www.myadaptec.com](http://www.myadaptec.com/). These sites are targeted towards current and potential Adaptec product resellers, distributors, retail companies and third-party consultants who buy Adaptec products and not to the general public; therefore the information practices vary somewhat regarding collection of information from the other Adaptec Web sites. Participants may provide extensive information both on and offline about their business in order to join the programs. We do reserve the right to match resellers to point of sale activity collected from distributors, track all activity and interests as they navigate the Web sites using cookies or other electronic tags and ask them frequent questions online and through third-party telemarketing efforts to help manage our reseller/distributor relationships. Information collected is stored in our database. Adaptec mines this database in an ongoing manner to market to resellers with as much insight into their business interests and business model as possible. In the event a potential reseller opts out, the data is not deleted from the database but Adaptec will make reasonable efforts to ensure that no further contact occurs unless the potential reseller requests it. If a member opts out, they may lose all privileges and access to the entire program and the data we have collected is identified as inactive and we make every reasonable effort to ensure that it is no longer included in future marketing campaigns. However, if a memberopts out of receiving e-mail communications, Adaptec makes all reasonable efforts to ensure that the member no longer receives e-mail contact except to the extent the member does have the ability to continue to access otherprogram Web sites to which member remains a member.

Online Surveys   

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like not be used for future marketing purposes, unless explicitly stated. In the event you are a reseller entering through adaptecconnect.com please refer to the section above regarding information collected.

Sharing Information with Other Companies and Individuals   

Adaptec reserves the right to share customer data with Adaptec's subsidiaries, affiliates, contractors, service vendors, advisors, accountants, auditors and temporary employees but only for the purpose of fulfilling its legitimate business interests as described in this Privacy Policy. Additionally, Adaptec reserves the right to transfer customer data to other entities as part of business transactions such as, but not limited to, spin-offs, acquisitions, mergers, reorganizations or liquidations. With your permission, Adaptec may share your information with its subsidiaries, affiliates and some of our valued partners. Please see the opt-in box on our Product Registration form. If you check that box, Adaptec may allow its subsidiaries, affiliates and partners to contact you via email or direct mail with products or services that we think might be of interest to our customers. Additionally, upon registering select products, you may be asked during the registration process if we may share your registration history with a specific partner or Original Equipment Manufacturer (OEM) who has either bundled an Adaptec product with theirs or their product with ours. We recommend you agree to this, so that you can receive important updates from the manufacturer of this bundled product. However, we suggest you review their Privacy Policy, as their practices may differ from ours. While Adaptec strives to ensure that all of these third parties protect the information in a manner at least as protective as our policy, we are not responsible for their practices.

User Information may be made available to or at the direction of legal and regulatory authorities (including tax authorities) if required by the public authorities as well as to Adaptec's professional advisers subject to professional obligations for data confidentiality.

Message Boards and Blogs   

Adaptec is now hosting a message board for the Linux community and participates in some of the discussions, although not all forums are currently monitored. To join the Message Board you will need to provide us with a login name, or nickname, and your full name, which will both be used to identify you when posting to the forum and agree to the applicable terms of use. Also a valid email address is required so that we can email your forum password to you. You may also opt to receive an optional community newsletter at this address. Adaptec will not use forum information for marketing or solicitation purposes. But please note that disclosing personally identifiable information online through Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards makes the information submitted public, even though the forum is limited to registered members. Such disclosure may increase the chance of you receiving "spam" or unsolicited email. Adaptec is not liable for any "spam" or unsolicited email generated from these boards. Be careful and use discretion when disclosing information online.

Notifications of Changes   

If we would like to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will make every effort to notify you via the last email address we have in our records. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases when we post the notice, we will also email users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

Unsubscribing/Opt-Out   

We frequently provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and/or our partners at the point where we request your information. Also, in our e-mail communications you will find instructions for unsubscribing. Adaptec seeks to comply with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 and will always strive to maintain a good relationship when contacting our customers and site visitors.

Additionally you may use one of the following options to request removal of your information from our databases. Please include the exact contact information you'd like removed and some detail about the type of communication you received from us.

**For EMEA :  
** You can send an email to  [EMEA_CustServ@adaptec.com](mailto:EMEA_CustServ@adaptec.com)

You can send mail to the following postal address:   
Adaptec Ltd.  
Marketing Department  
4 Archipelago  
Lyon Way  
Camberley  
Surrey  
GU16 5ER  
United Kingdom 

You can call the Adaptec Customer Service Dept. for non-technical questions only*  
+49.89.43.66.55.45 (English)  
+49.89.43.66.55.25 (German)  
+49.89.43.66.55.35 (French)

 **For North America :  
** You can send email to [Adaptec Privacy Policy](http://www.adaptec.com/forms/company_privacy_form.html)

You can send mail to the following postal address:  
Adaptec, Inc.  
Attn: Web Marketing, M/S 105   
691 S. Milpitas Blvd. Milpitas, CA 95035 

You can call the Adaptec Customer Service Dept. **_for non-technical questions only*  
_  
Hours of business are:  
**09:00 - 12:00, 13:00 - 16:00 CET

* For tech support questions you will need to contact tech support directly. 

Most email communications provide a uniquely coded URL so customers can unsubscribe from individual lists. To unsubscribe from the Adaptec Online Store newsletter, please email [adaptecstore@adaptec.com](mailto:adaptecstore@adaptec.com)  Put UNSUBSCRIBE ADAPTEC at the top of the message body.

Access to, Correcting or Updating your Personal Info   

To inquire about accessing your personal data, please contact us by one of the methods described below. We will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data that we keep about you, although we will require proof of your identity before disclosing that data. There may be a small charge for the provision of copies of your personal data. You may challenge the data that we hold about you and, where appropriate, you may have the data erased, rectified, amended or completed. We reserve the right to refuse to provide our visitors with a copy of their personal data, but will give reasons for our refusal. You will be able to challenge our decision to refuse to provide you with a copy of your personal data

To change or modify or remove information previously provided, we recommend that you reply or contact that list source directly. If no instructions were provided for updating your contact information you can submit a request containing your 'old' contact information, your 'new' contact information and the nature of the communication(s) you've received:

You can send email to:

 **For North America:**  
You can send an email to [Adaptec Privacy Policy  
](http:///)  
You can send mail to the following postal address:  
Adaptec, Inc.  
Attn: Web Marketing, M/S 160  
691 S. Milpitas Blvd. Milpitas, CA 95035   
You can call the Adaptec Customer Service Dept. for non-technical questions only*

 **For EMEA:**   

You can send mail to the following postal address:  
Adaptec Ltd.  
Marketing Department  
4 Archipelago  
Lyon Way  
Camberley  
Surrey  
GU16 5ER  
United Kingdom 

Or telephone any of the following numbers during hours of business:  
+49.89.43.66.55.45 (English)  
+49.89.43.66.55.25 (German)  
+49.89.43.66.55.35 (French)

 **Hours of business are:  
** 09:00 - 12:00, 13:00 - 16:00 CET

* For tech support questions you will need to contact tech support directly.

All other non-Web related requests should be directed to our main office in the United States, 408-957--2550

Please note that Adaptec reserves the right to preserve certain information collected when its software is downloaded from our Web site in order to protect Adaptec's proprietary rights to the software.  
 **  
Australian Users :  
** The contact details for Adaptec Australia are:  
Adaptec Australia   
Unit E1, 15 Forrester St  
Kingsgrove NSW 2208  
Australia  
t: 612-9503-1555   
f: 612-9503-1500  
[Demetri@adaptec.com](mailto:Demetri@adaptec.com)Upon your request, Adaptec Australia will provide you with information it holds about you, except in certain circumstances permitted by Australian law.

Information We Automatically Collect   

For each Web visitor we record date & time of visit, IP address and browser type to analyze how visitors use our site and to gather broad demographic information like country of origin and browser usage among our visitors. This information will not be matched against your personal information as supplied through all the means disclosed above. This information is analyzed and then purged on a regular basis.

This site contains links to other sites. [www.adaptec.com](http://www.adaptec.com/) is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statement of these linked sites, because their privacy practices may differ from ours.

Cookies   

A cookie is a piece of text asking permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. If you agree, then your browser adds the text in a small file. Cookies allow a Web application to respond to you as an individual and distinguish you from other visitors on the site at the same time. Cookies do not allow us to determine personal information about you. A few adaptec.com pages use temporary cookies as part of the Web navigation experience, for that particular web site session only. Temporary cookies are deleted when you close your browser. Some examples include Web site surveys and our Online Store. If you deny the cookie, you can still use the site anonymously. Customers in our on-line store can browse with cookies turned off, but you can only purchase if you accept the cookie. Adaptec Platinum drops a cookie with a temporary user ID only after you login to the site. This is to enhance the Web navigation experience. Our European site, www.adaptec-europe.com, will deposit a cookie related to your selected language preference so that we can direct you to that language more quickly when you return to the site on a future visit. Access to this site is hindered without the cookie.

Privacy and Children   

Adaptec and the Adaptec Web sites do not target children (defined as those persons under 13 years of age) as an audience or a market and Adaptec does not collect information about the age of its Web site users. Adaptec intends to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998. If we learn that we have inadvertently collected personal information from a child we will make all reasonable efforts to delete that data from our records.

Security   

To protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Our Online Store for North America is currently hosted by Commerce 5 but this may change from time to time in accordance with posted changes in this Online Store section of the Privacy Policy. To view Commerce5's privacy policy and security statement we welcome you to visit <http://www.digitalriver.com/corporate/privacy.shtml>

Adaptec strives to protect the privacy of the information you provide, and inadvertent disclosure of that information is extremely unlikely. In the event of such an inadvertent disclosure, Adaptec will do everything commercially reasonable to limit and remedy the disclosure, but Adaptec accepts no liability for any unintentional disclosure or a disclosure that occurs due to a security breach of our systems or facilities. In addition, in the unlikely event that any government or private individual seeks information, Adaptec will not voluntarily provide the information, but will obey any court order requiring disclosure.

Contact   

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact: 

**For North America:  
** [Adaptec Privacy Policy ](http://www.adaptec.com/forms/company_privacy_form.html)or phone Adaptec Customer Service at either1-800-959-7274 or 1-408-957-2550 

**Hours of business are:  
** Monday - Friday (except holidays ) 6:00 AM - 5:00 PM U.S. Pacific Time   
**  
For EMEA:  
or phone Adaptec Customer Service at   
+49.89.43.66.55.45 (English)  
+49.89.43.66.55.25 (German)  
+49.89.43.66.55.35 (French)

 **Hours of business are:  
** 09:00 - 12:00, 13:00 - 16:00 CET
